Academic Programs and Priorities, Select Committee on; Records ua010.003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Select Committee on Academic Programs and Priorities Collection1975-1977
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York.
ua010.003
1.4
Collection is made up of materials about proposed improvements for the University's programs in the 1970s.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in the order it was received.
Biographical / Historical
The Select Committee on Academic Program Priorities was created by the president of the University at Albany. It was created as away to assess the success of the school and create recommendations on what to improve in each academic program. It operated in the mid 1970's making long term plans for each college or department.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this group is unrestricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Scope and Contents
Collection is made up of documents pertaining to administrative reports made by the Select Committee on Academic Program and Priorities. Items include meeting minutes, division reports, background reports, and resource schema. These detail proposed changes detailed how to improve individual programs to make them more effective and rigourous, while also improving graduation rate.
Educational reports; Universities and Colleges--New York (State)--Administration; UAlbany Task Forces & Committees
- Priorities, Responses, 1975 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic Program Recommendations, 1975 May-1975 August (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Select Committee General Report, 1975 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Task Force on Priorities and Resources, 1976 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Select Committee Final Report, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Select Committee Background Reports - Arts & Sciences, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Select Committee Background Reports - Humanities, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Background Reports - Science and Math Division, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Background Reports - Social Sciences, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Background Reports - Graduate Education, 1973 January-1974 October (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Background Reports - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General Report and Recommendations, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- General Report Responses, 1975 May-1975 August (Box 1, Folder 13)
- General Report Responses, 1975 May-1975 June (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Collected General Report Responses, 1975 May (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Specific Program Recommendations, 1975 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
- President's Statements on Academic Priorities, 1975 January-1975 July (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Vice President's Copy of the General Report, 1976 February (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Academic Advisement, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Allen Collegiate Center Collected Responses, 1975 May (Box 2, Folder 6)